[Music]
Welcome to new busy central launch
edition 2025 release wave 2. Today we
will present what is new in documents
related to new draft page for electronic
voices. My name is Alexander Toto. I'm
product manager responsible for e
documents and I have my colleague with
me today.
>> Hello, my name is Manos and I am a
engineer in the business central team.
Thank you Magnus. So first let's look
into business value from these
functionalities.
Uh with enabling draft page you will see
how it's working uh in a few minutes.
First it will improve uh invoice
accuracy a lot because you can now
review refine your incoming document
before posting. So any error if any
error appear or any inaccurate uh
information is there you can easily uh
it change even if you are missing item
references or GL account mapping. So
further it will streamline invoice
processing especially for electronic
invoice processing pay invoicing. It
will ensure smoother workflow. Um and we
will use actually tool. This draft page
is very similar what is used by payable
agent and of course it will enhance uh
compliance and control because now you
have this additional option option to
review all these documents before from
financial perspective and adding the
measures whatever is necessary deferrals
and so on before you proceed with the
posting. So let's make a look uh in the
workflow we had earlier. So earlier this
is what we had. You could set up a
vendor to receive invoice or order. If
it uh receive an invoice, system will
create new purchase invoice and will
receive electronic invoice from one of
services. If orders are there, if order
doesn't exist, system will create new
purchase order. If order exist uh system
will go to matching uh using copilot or
manually matching with existing purchase
order and update purchase order. But now
with new draft page what will happen
when you receive your invoice system
will use draft page if you set up this
way and then you can connect lines in
the draft page. If you set up your
document to receive invoices from draft
page, you will create purchase invoice.
If setup is on a vendor side to use
orders, system will create new order. So
now I want to explain in this moment we
will have two different setups. So the
old one will enable you to create new
invoice or create or update existing
purchase order. with new setup.
Currently you can create purchase
invoice to purchase order but using
draft page with a really great set of
functionalities. So you cannot use in
this moment both of these features. So
this is on you. Please start with the
sandbox look what is the best for you
and we will continue to improve this
functionality extending with the new
options in the future. So Magnus please
show us.
>> Yes. Yes. Let's take a look at how this
is in the demo. So Alexander you just
mentioned that that you actually have to
go configure this in order to use the
new draft uh page. So I'll just show
that we can go to our e document
services and here I have created the
standard one we have usually e documents
and then our e document version one
which would will be the old uh way of
processing uh documents. So if we go to
this e documents we can see that I under
importing fast tab have selected uh the
import process here to be version two.
So before what we originally shipped and
all of uh the workflow that we had uh
previously all fell under uh version one
and now with version two you'll have to
select which format you want to read
into the draft with. And I have selected
pebble for today's uh uh demonstration.
But just to look how it was before
before we we look at how it is uh now I
have this demo invoice uh 25 and that is
used processing the the old uh version
one and you can see here actually that
we do have the lines but we don't have
any interaction with the lines on this
page. We also have the the header
fields, but there's not really anything
you can do. And if you want to um map
these lines into, for instance, items or
accounts in BC, you would need to go and
actually set up item references. And
there's no way to get there. And there's
not like a very good flow of actually
processing the invoice here.
I will go ahead and delete it. And then
I will upload it again using the new
service so we can see the difference.
I will select e documents here and then
I will click this one and I will just go
open draft document.
It thinks a little bit because it's
processing in the background. And now we
can see the page looks quite different.
So we still have the general fast tab
with header information. And here you
can go edit dates, numbers. Um you can
even change the vendor if we don't
manage in so in some cases we won't
manage to find a vendor based on the
document you're providing. This could be
because we can't find anything with a
VAT number or the name and address don't
match. But you can then go and choose a
value for the vendor yourself. You can
do a lookup and then this way you can
select. Then we can also see that all of
the lines are now editable. And that
means that we can actually go change
both the quantities and the prices and
units of measures descriptions and and
so on. And what we really want to focus
on in this demonstration is of course
the type and number. So for this
demonstration, you can see that both
type and number for all three lines I
have in this invoice are filled out. And
we also get these small information
icons that will tell us how we managed
to fill it out, where it comes from, and
so on. So let's let's see here. The
first line, the desk I have was filled
out using an item reference because
there is a a value in the item reference
number. And if we click it, we can see
that item reference was found for vendor
4,000. We can even navigate to the
source where we actually got this
information from. So if I click that, it
will open up your item reference list
filter down to the specific entry.
The same goes for the second line. So
that's like super interesting. But that
will be the first thing we try to do for
all lines is to actually go in and and
look at your configuration in the setup
using item references or using text to
account mapping.
After that some lines might still be not
processed or not found a type and number
for and that is for instance this uh
third line which is a delivery cost for
delivering these items. And in this case
if we click at the number there is an
account filled out but where did we
actually get this from? So if I click on
that we can see that this is actually
picked up by exact description match
recent purchase for the same vendor. So
that is a historical match and that is
that whenever we are on this draft page
and we process these lines we will look
at previously posted invoices to see if
we can find similar lines that we can
then use to identify new lines with. So
in this case we actually have a posted
purchase invoice. If I click that, it
will open up that page and we can
inspect this uh posted purchase invoice,
see which account was chosen. And you
can see this is just a duplicate of the
previous one for today's demonstration.
But here, delivery cost was put uh to
this uh specific general ledger account.
And the final thing that will happen,
say we don't find any history, then we
have a fall back to using uh AI
specifically to try for now to try and
identify a general ledger account that
can be used. And I thought I wanted to
show you that as well. So I'll just jump
back to the list and look at the first
invoice I uploaded because at that time
there were no history and as you can see
it still managed to find an account. But
if we look at the details about the
suggestion, we now get a explanation
from the AI saying exactly why is it
that it thinks that delivery cost should
be classified for freight fees for goods
on this account and then it will
explain.
I'll just go back to the invoice we were
processing. So this one. So once you
have actually filled out all the lines,
you can then go ahead and click finalize
draft. And this will then create the
purchase invoice. And from here you can
either set additional things if you so
desire or just post it. It is ready for
that. So this new workflow experience is
much more allowing hands-on for the user
to go and correct and and adjust and
work with the draft until it's ready for
actually creating a invoice. Yes. And
that is uh all about the new draft page.
>> Thank you, Magnus.
So just to explain this functionality
will be in a public preview. This is
important and it will come in one of
next minor. So it will not be in
October. So it will come after that in
one of minors. You can track on a
release plan uh exact information and it
will be in the public preview. So please
for the beginning try this in the
sandbox. So before we close the session
again general information you can find
one of these links very interesting. You
can learn a lot. Then do not forget
subscribe on our LinkedIn channel. You
can track weekly news all announcements
related to Busy Central and AKM SBC
YouTube to watch this session where you
already watched this session and you can
find another session about the documents
about whole edition and previous
editions as well. So thank you for
watching this session.